So the first step in the eye treatment, in the soothing eye treatment, would be to remove any makeup that your client might be wearing.
And today Jen is wearing a little mascara and eye shadow so I'm just going to gently using a makeup removing, you know cleanser or eye makeup remover.
You just want to go over the eye area and kind of wipe down very gently and then away from the inner eye.
And it might take a few cotton pads.
And the reason why I'm going away from the eye area is that's just to avoid any infection or irritation.
Usually people's eyes are pretty sensitive especially with allergies and all the above so by moving away from the eye you are just avoiding potential hazard for the future.
If someone is coming straight from work or you know just had to do errands and usually wears makeup that's just fine, usually the makeup removing part of any treatment is you know complimentary and included in any facial or eye treatment so you don't need to tell your clients, you know to come in without any makeup on.
Usually when people are complaining of tired or stressed looking eyes, makeup is the first thing that they go for, so whatever you know your clients are doing to help brighten or open or de-stress their eyes is probably fine and what makes them comfortable, so definitely don't discourage your clients in doing their regular routine.
But of course getting an eye treatment is, would be beneficial in helping to reduce their concerns.
And this is the makeup removing part of the eye treatment.